# 今天应网友的要求
Today, as requested by many fans,
# 做一家庭版的佛跳墙
We are going to make a home style Buddha's Temptation
# 其实佛跳墙有三个版本
There are actually three versions
# 最原始的版本里边有
The original version has
# 鲍鱼 海参 鱼翅 裙边 干贝
abalone, sea cucumber, shark fin, softshell turtle shell, dried scallop
# 鸽蛋等等  基本上都是好料
Pigeon eggs. Basically all the fancy ingredients.
# 二一版的佛跳墙呢
A not-so-fancy version of this dish is
# 海鲜佛跳墙  虾球 扇贝 大瑶柱
The seafood version. It has shrimps, scallops and large scallops
# 全是海鲜品
All seafood
# 现在有好多开了一些素宴
Nowadays in some of those vegetarian banquets
# 菌类佛跳墙
They have mushroom version of Buddha's temptation
# 黄耳 银耳 竹荪 羊肚菌 松茸等等
Yellow Ear, snow fungus, bamboo mushrooms, true morels, matsutake and so on.
# 今天呢咱们就做一家庭版的
Today we are going to make a home cook version
# 不管做什么佛跳墙
No matter which version of Buddha's temptation
# 还得吊好汤的  对
A great stock is essential, yep.
# 没好汤其他不能聊
Nothing else matters without a great stock
# 猪棒骨  老母鸡  肘子
Pork leg bone, hen, pork knuckle
# 熬这汤还是凉水下锅
For this soup we start from cold water
# 等它慢慢开
Let it sit in the back burner
# 开了以后把沫子打净
Then skim off the scum and foam
# 今儿还砸么  也砸也吊
Do we Diao or Za today? Or we do both?
# 不吊  今天用的是浓汤
Nope we are using a thick stock today
# 汤先炖着  咱们准备点食材
Let the stock simmer on the side. Let's prep the ingredients
# 家庭版佛跳墙
Home style Buddha's temptation
# 就是家里有啥就给啥
Use everything you could find at home
# 把这个虾线去掉
Devein the shrimp
# 一通百通叫大家学得会
You can apply the same technique to other dishes
# 今天大爷把这佛跳墙
Today Da Ye
# 稍微的简版了一下
Slightly simplified this dish
# 主要是让大家能在家能做
So that you all can make this at home
# 有什么食材用什么食材
Use anything you can find at home
# 鲍鱼  这鲍鱼个儿不小
Abalone, this one's got quite a size
# 活鲍鱼  这鲍鱼不便宜啊
Live abalone, this could cost a fortune
# 不便宜  二十五
Not cheap, 25 Yuan
# 洗鲍鱼呢 你看有层黑膜
Washing abalone, you can see there's a black membrane
# 弄点盐  淀粉
Get some salt and starch
# 洗洗它的粘液  增白
Wash off its slime and whitening it up
# 盐呢它去掉鲍鱼的粘液  也是去腥
Salt removes it's slime as well as remove the fishy smell
# 淀粉它会把里边污的东西
Starch brings the dirty stuff out
# 脏的东西都能通过
Dirty stuff can be
# 淀粉的摩擦  它就全掉了
Rubbed off using starch,
# 人说了  最干净是您那双手
They say your hands are the cleanest part
# 我们在这个背面打小十字花刀
Lets score diagonal cuts in a crisscross pattern
# 宽细均匀你看看
Look how they are uniformly cut
# 深浅也合适  宝刀不老啊
And the depth is appropriate as well, you are still good at it
# 鲍鱼处理完了啊
We've finished with the abalones
# 您说说这海参  刚想起来
Now lets talk about the sea cucumber just as I remembered
# 中国人讲究吃海参要吃刺参
In China we prefer spiky sea cucumbers
# 必须带刺
Gotta have spikes
# 要不带刺感觉就不像参似的
It doesn't feel like a sea cucumber without the spikes
# 我们今天选这海参是
These sea cucumbers we picked today are
# 葫芦岛野生六年的海参
Six-year, harvested in Huludao
# 这还是即食的  开袋就可以加工
And it's ready to eat, open the bag and you are ready to cook
# 我们稍微给它修整一下
Let's trim it a little
# 我们严格的说得用鸽蛋
Strictly speaking we need to use pigeon eggs
# 今天咱们是用鹌鹑蛋
But today we are using quail eggs
# 这是煮熟了的  剥好了皮儿
Hard boiled and shells are removed
# 我们家里如果有条件可以买点
If we can, it would be good to buy some
# 大的瑶柱啊  大干贝啊
Large scallops and Conpoy
# 没有呢也没关系  其实现在也不贵
If not, that's also ok. Plus its not expensive nowadays
# 给老人做点好吃的  提什么贵啊
Cooking for elderlies we don't talk about the price
# 佛跳墙关键的调味品在哪
The key seasoning for this dish is
# 在这儿  哈哈  来啦
Here, haha here it is
# 黄酒
Huangjiu (Yellow wine)
# 不管什么品牌的黄酒
Doesn't matter which brand
# 做这个佛跳墙要用点好黄酒
We have to use some decent yellow wine
# 没有好黄酒很本不叫佛跳墙
Without decent yellow wine it can't even be called the buddha's temptation
# 在最初原始的佛跳墙
The original version of this dish
# 其实都是以黄酒为主
Was mainly cooked with yellow wine
# 你看这汤啊  把这个沫子要打干净
Look at the stock, froth must be cleaned throughly
# 锅稍微小点啊
This pot is a little small
# 家里头不可能有那些顺手的家伙
You can't always get those handy utilities at home
# 不是大点啦就是小点啦
It's always too big or too small
# 但是我们把前期处理的事儿
But we prepared it well enough
# 给它弄好了
Straighten it up
# 心 细  就能做到完美的结果
With care you can achieve the perfect result
# 咱们选鸡得选什么样的鸡啊
What type of chicken are we looking for
# 一般的吊汤的鸡
Normally speaking chicken used in making stock
# 都是三年以上的老母鸡
Must be hen aged over 3 years
# 找不出三年的啊  一年的行不行啊
If we can't find over 3 years, would 1 year do?
# 一年也行
That will work
# 拿温水洗  不能拿凉水
Wash with warm water, not with cold water
# 凉水就给激回去了
Cold water will shrink it back
# 另外凉水洗不干净
Besides cold water can't wash it throughly
# 鸡油一招凉水就凝固了
Chicken oil turns solid once washed with cold water
# 鸡头不要了啊
Ditch the chicken head
# 还有一些浮在肉上的浮沫
And some scum on the top
# 还是我在老饭骨前期节目说过的
We've mentioned this in our previous videos
# 炖汤以前炖五六个小时
We used to leave the stock on back burner for 5-6 hours
# 我感觉这里边的嘌呤还是不好的
Now I feel like the purine in it is not so good for your health
# 因为在家里做饭么  要缩短时间
Because we are cooking at home, we need to save time
# 那就用高压锅
We use a pressure cooker
# 但是我们在前期处理完了以后
But only when we finished pre-processing the chicken
# 才能用高压锅
We can use pressure cooker
# 这个汤你看没有沫子了
Now you don't see any foam on the top
# 倒到这里头
Pour it in here
# 扣上
Put the lid on
# 五十分钟之后就OK了
Let it sit for 50 mins
# 那现在您干点什么啊
What do you do now
# 现在这活儿接着就来啦
Here come other jobs
# 这里边搁点葱  姜  黄酒
Add some spring onion, ginger, yellow wine
# 我们鲍鱼海参要飞水
We need to blanch the abalone
# 要去去它的腥味
Get rid of its bad smells
# 凡是有异味的都得用
Anything with a bad smell must use
# 葱姜酒水去去除它的味道
Ginger, spring onion and yellow wine infused water to get rid of its bad smell
# 还不能有油
We can't have oil in it
# 先把这鲍鱼下去  小花让它开开
Add these abalones, let the flower blossom
# 这个烫的时间别太长
Around 15 seconds
# 基本就是十五秒钟
Once the flowers are blossomed
# 小花儿一开就行
Looking good right? Now add the sea cucumbers
# 漂亮吧  海参下去
It can be cooked for a little longer
# 海参下去可以多煮一会
Don't leave it in for too lone
# 去掉它的腥味  搁点盐
Get rid of its fishy smell, add a pinch of salt
# 看这刺  饱满
Look at these spikes, round and pointy
# 把虾仁烫一下
Slightly cook the shrimps
# 一进一出一打卷出锅了就
Fish it out once it curls up
# 这个叫分别把各种原材料
This is called
# 进行前期的热处理
Heat treatment for each ingredient
# 也叫初步加工
Also known as pre-cook
# 出锅啦  好看
Look at that
# 一个一个小牡丹似的  牡丹花
Looks like little peonies
# 牡丹虾  鲍鱼  海参
Shrimps, abalones and sea cucumbers
# 还有鸽蛋
"pigeon" eggs
# 大爷说应该是鸽子蛋
Da Ye says it's supposed to be pigeon eggs
# 今天咱们是鹌鹑蛋
Today we are using quail eggs
# 咱们按实际的跟你们讲
Let me tell you the truth
# 看见没有
Look
# 为什么把这鹌鹑蛋烫一下
Why do I rinse the quail eggs with hot water
# 容易上色 你要冷的上不去
For better colouring, you can't get the same colouring with cold eggs
# 老抽啊  这就是小点子大家别忘了
And dark soy sauce, don't forget these tricks
# 这个以前师父没给我讲过啊
My master had never mentioned these to me
# 提意见了啊
Someone has some complaints
# 先给我来点油吧
Give me some oil first
# 三叔啊  隋坡啊  看着
San Shu and Sui Po look at this
# 上颜色了吧  你要如果说不加热
Its getting some colour on it, if its not heated
# 这个鹌鹑蛋不加热
If these quail eggs were not heated
# 这个老抽上不去
The dark soy sauce won't get its colour on it
# 现在我们油也热了
Now the oil is heated
# 我怎么不知道啊  你没跟三叔说啊
How come I don't know about that, you never told San Shu.
# 不让您知道  你不用动勺了
You don't have to know about this and don't have to worry about it
# 实际上就是过去我们
Actually this is how we used to make
# 虎皮蛋烧肘子
Hu Pi eggs with pork knuckles
# 把鸡蛋先炸一下  它炸出来香
Deep fry the eggs to bring out the aroma
# 还有一师父讲过叫逢烧必炸
And master once said "Feng Shao Bi Zha" (Must deep-fry if we need to shao )
# 逢烧必炸  用于吸味  差不多了啊
It is used to absorb flavours
# 你看这小鸡蛋儿
Check these tiny eggs
# 小鸡蛋（鹌鹑蛋）炸出来了啊
Tiny eggs (quail eggs) are fried
# 咱们的汤也煲好了  大爷该动手了
And our soup is done, it Da Ye's turn
# 马上呈现出咱们最美好的
We are about to present the best of
# 家庭版的佛跳墙
Home style buddha's temptation
# 这小罐地道  佛跳墙
This pot is really authentic
# 家庭版的佛跳墙
Home style buddha's temptation
# 我们就得做到物尽其用
We need to use everything to its last bit
# 佛跳墙里边也得搁点（肘子）
Let's add some pork knuckle
# 又香  口感又烂糊
Smells so good, with very tender and mushy texture
# 我要是你我就不切了
If I were you I wouldn't cut it
# 我就直接大块吃了
I'd eat it straight up
# 把这肉垫在底下  再来点鸡块  鸡肉
Put this at the bottom and add some chicken
# 你看 多么实惠
Look how affordable this is
# 搁点蘑菇  这叫什么菇啊
Add some mushrooms, what are these
# 白玉菇  蟹腿菇
Shimeji mushrooms
# 把这个蘑菇出出水
Wilt these mushrooms
# 放点盐  进点小底味
Add a bit of salt to set the base tone
# 来点鸡汤  鸡汤开始下了啊
Some chicken stock, add some chicken stock
# 几勺啊  来两勺  给我来点老抽
A few spoons of dark soy sauce
# 调点色  黄酒  把这蘑菇回锅
Adjust the colour, yellow wine and add these mushrooms back in the wok
# 煨一下  搁点盐
Let it bubble for a while and add some salt
# 您刚才是不搁过一次盐了么
Haven't you already added once
# 那是搁水里边的
That was into the water
# 这是搁什么里的  这是搁汤里的
What is this for then? This is for the soup
# 水和汤还是不一样
Oh that's different
# 搁点糖  中和了它的味道
Add some sugar to balance the flavour
# 这就好啦
There we go
# 下边呢海参  鲍鱼一块煨
At the bottom there are sea cucumbers and abalones being strewed together
# 虾球煨进去  鹌鹑蛋
Shrimps and quail eggs
# 来点胡椒粉  胡椒粉啊
Add a pinch of ground pepper
# 把这些东西都煨好了以后
Once they are all cooked
# 我们开始往罐儿里摆放
We place them into the pot
# 佛跳墙  先搁虾仁  垫下边
For the buddha's temptation, shrimps go in first
# 翠绿翠绿的小菜心
Green bok choy hearts
# 这汤没用了  我们还用鸡汤
This is useless, we use chicken stock
# 再调一汤  好
Lets make another broth
# 鸡汤里调点糖（和盐）
Add some sugar and salt in the chicken stock
# 因为咱们的佛跳墙
Our dish can not be
# 不能是愣咸愣咸的
Simply salty taste
# 我们老饭骨又不搁鸡精味精的
We don't use MSG or chicken powder
# 所以用糖来平衡味道
So we use sugar to balance the taste
# 酒（黄酒）  酒一勺
One spoon of yellow wine
# 来点老抽
A drizzle of dark soy sauce
# 原则上一般的不勾芡
Normally we don't thicken it (with slurry)
# 为什么呢  因为它有鹿筋呐
Why? Because it has deers tendons
# 蹄筋啊  胶原蛋白比较多的
Which contains plenty of collagen
# 那就不勾芡
Then we don't add slurry
# 因为咱们今天做的是家庭版的
Because we are making home style version
# 让它有浓厚的的味道
To give it a fuller mouthfeel
# 且今天的食材不用提前备
Plus we don't need prepare much on the ingredients
# 满足我们想吃就吃的状态
We can eat whenever we feel like
# 随时吃  这汁红亮
Anytime, look at the sauce
# 这粉劲儿有点小
This starch doesn't thicken very well
# 一个方向转一转
Stir in the same direction
# 走不叫走  走你  叫行
Here we go
# 端得动么  倒了啊
Can you hold it? I'm about to pour it
# 这都是好汤
This is such a great broth
# 上锅吧  最好呢有个棉纸
Put it on the stove, better have a cotton paper
# 上头一盖  对一盖
Cover the top up, right lid on
# 一小时了我给你掐着点儿呢
One hour already I've been counting the time
# 忘了跟网友交代了
Forgot to tell you all about this
# 您为什么蒸一下
Why to you steam it
# 实际上传统的佛跳墙要炖几个小时
Normally it takes hours to make this dish
# 但是那都是属于干货涨发
But that was to soak up these dried ingredients
# 就是那些海味品
Those seafood
# 它那需要一个长时间的炖制
It needs a long time on the stove
# 因为家庭版么  家庭条件有限
Because it's home style and with limited equipment
# 有的用保鲜膜  保持这个酒的香味
Some use cling wrap to keep the aroma of the wine
# 看着就香啊  看着香吧
It looks so delicious
# 那今天这罐正好够咱仨
This pot is just the right amount for us three
# 咱们吃的时候别叫四弟
Don't tell brother Si
# 谁也别叫  不许吭声  悄悄的
Don't let him know, lets enjoy this behind his back
# 三叔尝尝  烫不烫啊  有点烫啊
San shu have a taste, is it hot? A little bit?
# 吹吹  怎么样  大爷
Blow it a bit, how's it? Da Ye?
# 先甭说味儿  您这海参
Beside the taste, just look at the sea cucumbers
# 前后掌握的火候特别好
The cooking time is managed really well
# 没有腥味吧  处理的好吧
You don't taste any fishy smells right? It's cleaned so well
# 处理太好了  让我们徒弟尝尝
It's done so well, let our apprentices have a taste
# 你看看大爷就是大爷
Look Da Ye is such a master
# 先紧着我们群众
He holds us back
# 他能控制住情绪
And controls the emotions
# 有人来了  听见有人来吧
Someone's coming, I can hear the sound
# 快快这小伙子
Quick quick young fella
# 哎呦大爷  我掐指一算
Da Ye, I figured
# 录上录上
Record that
# 我掐指一算我大爷这个佛跳墙出锅了
I figured your buddha's temptation has came out of the pot
# 小焦来了  先给您请安
Xiao Jiao has arrived, he greets you first
# 师侄来吧
Master's nephew come
# 浓郁  唇齿留香
Rich flavour and the taste lingers around your mouth
# 匠心永不工业化
Artisans spirits can never be industrialised
# 这真的是传承啊  匠心啊
This is real heritage, artisans' craftsmanship
# 太厉害了  厉害吧
This is awesome!
# 你们说的都是真的
You are telling the truth
# 我们谢谢大爷吧  谢谢大爷
Let's thank Da Ye
# 你给大爷鞠个躬
Take a bow to Da Ye
# 我给大爷点个赞
I'll give Da Ye a thumbs up
# import ending.srt 00:11:50,300